翻譯：餓得慌    zhanginfo    wdjmhs    衛老哥
■
翻譯：幸田實果子    莎友友    我才是怪蜀黍    橫排混血
時間軸：紫熏   憑陵新月    校對：wdjmhs    餓得慌
■
精校：壞?小泡   后期：冰河   監制：wdjmhs
國土安全
第三季 第九集
美國空軍及海軍
Air and naval forces of the United States
對恐怖組織發起了一系列攻擊
launched a series of strikes against terrorist facilities...
泛美航空103號班機于洛克比失事
Pan Am flight 103 crashed into the town of Lockerbie.
他已批準在非洲  歐洲和中東的恐怖行動
He has sanctioned acts of terror in Africa, Europe, the Middle East.
我們不容科威特遭受侵略
This will not stand, this aggression against Kuwait.
對于恐怖襲擊的不懈打擊
This relentless pursuit of terror.
我們將一視同仁
We will make no distinction...
美國軍艦科爾號
The USS Cole was attacked
在亞丁灣港口加油時遭到襲擊
while refueling in the port of Aden.
這是恐怖主義行動
This was an act of terrorism.
這是可鄙懦弱的行動
It was a despicable and cowardly act.
下面為您演奏的
The next samba we're going to swing for you
是一首經典曲目
is one of the good old favorites.
直到他受到了阻擊
...until something stops him.
整個事件就發生在我的眼前
It was right in front of my eyes,
而我絲毫沒預料到
and I never saw it coming.
該飛機撞向了世貿中心
That plane crashed into the World Trade Center.
成千上萬的民眾東奔西逃
Thousands of people running.
我們必須  也將在國內外保持警惕
We must and we will remain vigilant at home and abroad.
你是我見過最聰明  又最愚蠢的人
You're the smartest and the dumbest fucking person i've ever known.
我不是不明真相的那個人
I'm not the one who got it wrong.
我是唯一的明白人
I'm the only one who got it right.
拿下
Take 'em.
通通拿下
Take 'em all.
《國土安全》前情提要
Previously on Homeland:
我已經為你計劃好了
I got plans for you.
什么計劃
What plans?
我要把你放回伊朗
I'm gonna play you back into Iran.
從現在起  你為我們做事
From now on you work for us.
參議員義正言辭地對你提出了控訴
The senator's made some serious allegations.
說你把賈瓦迪藏進我們本土的安全屋
That you had Majid Javadi in a safe house on American soil
還送他出境
and let him go.
我們盤問了他  策反了他
We debriefed him, turned him.
他是我們的人了
He's ours.
我決定再給我們的婚姻一次機會
I've made a decision to give the marriage another chance.
他走之前告訴我一些事
And he told me something before he left...
關于總部炸彈襲擊者的事
about the Langley bomber.
你是說布洛迪
You mean Brody.
不  就是這點  不是他
No, that's just it. It's not him.
那個襲擊者是唯一可以證明布洛迪清白的人
The bomber's the only way to prove that Brody's innocent.
卡莉  你他媽要干啥
Carrie, what the fuck are you doing?
卡莉  馬上回去
Carrie, turn around now.
這是對你的最后警告
This is your last warning.
她左上臂受了槍傷
Got a gunshot wound to the upper left bicep.
大出血  可能是射穿動脈了
Significant bleeding. Might have clipped an artery.
索爾在他媽什么地方
Where the fuck is Saul?
你醒了
You're awake.
我這是在哪兒
Where am I?
海軍醫院
The Naval Hospital.
你中槍后被他們送了過來
They brought you here after you were shot.
小心點  別把傷口撐裂了
Careful, you don't want to rip the sutures.
縫了不少針
Quite a few of them.
子彈穿透了身體  沒傷到骨頭
It was a through and through. Missed the bone.
有肌肉和組織損傷  但沒傷到神經
Some muscle and tissue damage but no nerve involvement.
你很幸運
You're lucky.
不  是他槍法準
No, he's just a great shot.
我要在這里待多久
How long will I be in here?
該待多久就待多久
As long as you need to be.
是等我痊愈
For me to heal
還是等中情局想出處理我的辦法
or for the CIA to figure out what to do with me?
這事你得問他們
You'd have to talk to them.
你知道自己懷孕十三周了嗎
Are you aware you're 13 weeks pregnant?
知道
Yes.
孩子應該沒事
The baby should be fine.
如果你想知道的話
In case you're wondering.
瞳孔對光有反應
Pupils reactive to light.
高壓60  低壓40
BP of 60 over 40.
太他媽低了
Too fucking low.
躺下
Lay down.
他在飛機上毒癮發作
He started going cold turkey on the flight,
所以他們就用半斤伏特加把他灌暈了
so they knocked him out. With a half pint of Vodka.
一群白癡
Idiots.
脈搏微弱
Pulse is thready.
放松
Take it easy.
我的東西呢  你們這群屌賊
Where's my stuff, you fucking thieves?!
操  把東西還我
Fuck! Where is my stuff?!
冷靜  該死
Calm down, goddamn it!
我的東西呢
Where's my stuff?
別動
Don't move now.
在洛克哈特正式上任前  你還有七天時間
You've got seven days till Lockhart's confirmed.
你覺得這家伙到時能準備好嗎
You think this guy's gonna be ready by then?
我們沒想到他會變成那樣
He's not what we expected...
但他是我們唯一的籌碼
But he's what we've got.
如果他同意合作的話
If he agrees to do it.
他簡直一團糟
He's a mess:
貧血
Anemic...
嚴重脫水  可能還得了丙型肝炎
Severely dehydrated, probably Hep C.
無法確認是否感染艾滋病毒
HIV isn't a stretch.
如果你建議送他去醫院  我絕不會答應
If you're suggesting a hospital, it's out of the question.
我肯定能保住他的命
I'm pretty sure I can keep him stable,
可這家伙有毒癮
but the guy's a junkie, sir.
戒斷得多久
How far is he into withdrawal?
很困難
Hardly started.
他現在的情況
What he's feeling now,
會發展到非常可怕的地步
it's gonna get a hell of a lot worse.
美沙酮也許有點用
Methadone would make it easier.
必須完全戒掉
Has to be cold turkey.
無論如何都得讓他正常起來
Where he's going, we need him functional.
不怕搞死他嗎
Even if it kills him?
不會的
It won't.
有你負責保他的命
'Cause you will keep him alive.
懂了嗎
Do you understand?
收到
Sir.
沒事吧
You all right?
別動  你想干嘛
Stop! What are you doing?
我得來一針
I need it!
那邊沒有你要的東西
There's nothing there for you.
-我受不了了  -不行
- No, I need it now! - No.
給我  給我  給我
Damelo! Damelo! Dame...
摁住他
Hey, grab him!
針呢
Where's the needle?
來了
Got it.
蓋上他  摁住
Cover him up. Stay down.
求你了
Please...
感覺如何
How are you feeling?
醫生說你恢復得不錯
The doctor says you're progressing nicely.
很快就能起來活動了
You'll be up and walking in no time.
不過  估計不會讓你出病房
Though, not necessarily out of here.
門口有兩名警衛守著
There are two armed guards outside your door.
這一系列事件讓我深深地意識到
You know it never ceases to amaze me
你們有多么團結
how you people close ranks.
比如現在
Here you are,
你在中情局外勤任務中亂來而自食其果
a casualty of some CIA op gone very, very wrong,
基本上成了囚犯
basically a prisoner,
但不知道為什么  我卻成了敵人
and still, somehow, I'm the enemy.
你很清楚
You are aware
中情局人員
that the CIA charter does not include
禁止在本土行動
operations on U.S. soil?
我還在服用鎮痛劑
You know, I'm on painkillers.
基本不明白你的意思
I can barely understand anything you're saying.
好吧
Well...
我一直在看你的檔案
I've been going through your file.
事實上
The fact is,
你需要個靠得住的人
you need someone you can trust.
這話怎么講
And why is that?
你被一槍撂倒  總想問個究竟吧
You're lying there shot and you need to ask?
對你下這狠手那位
The man who did this to you,
馬上就要滾蛋了
he's on his way out.
可我還是想知道
But I need to know...
他的目的何在
what's he up to?
問他吧
Ask him.
他跑加拉加斯去干什么
What was he doing in Caracas?
恐怕你還不知道他去那里了吧
You didn't even know he was there, did you?
卡莉那里又有消息了
I got another message from Carrie.
她冷靜下來了吧
Is she calming down at all?
恰恰相反
No, the opposite.
洛克哈特議員去找她了
Senator Lockhart just paid her a visit.
他知道我們來加拉加斯了
Somehow, he knows about Caracas.
不可能
It's impossible.
反正他知道了
Well, he does.
你認為他起疑了
You think he suspects?
我確定他不知情
I'm sure he doesn't have a clue.
但她知道了
She does now.
那我們怎么辦
So what do we do about that?
老樣子
Same as before;
讓她就待在醫院
keep her under guard at the hospital.
不能見布洛迪
Away from Brody.
洛克哈特呢
And Lockhart?
真不知道他怎么知道的
I don't know how the hell he found out.
這事只有你知我知
No one knew besides us.
查查我們的家里和辦公室
Have our houses and offices swept.
所有房間都徹底查查
Every room, top to bottom.
什么情況
What happened?
拉了一身
Shat himself.
天吶
Jesus Christ.
你們是誰
Who are you?
別說話
Don't talk.
你們是軍方的吧
You're soldiers, aren't you?
別說話
Don't talk.
太燙了  燙死了
It's burning! It's burning.
水不熱
It's not hot.
太燙了
It's burning!
這種狀態  甚至更糟的情況還會持續三天
It'll continue as bad as this, or worse, another three days.
然后毒性從機體代謝
And at least a week after that
至少還得一周
before the stuff's out of his system.
就是說得十天了
So you're saying ten days.
我們只有六天
We have six.
而且等他緩過來
Plus, at the end of all this,
肯定也跟只慫貓一樣了
he's gonna be weak as a fuckin' kitten.
還有個辦法
There is another option.
什么
What?
伊菠因
Ibogaine.
一種尼日利亞植物中的萃取物
It's a drug based on a Nigerian plant.
它可以極大地加速戒毒進程
It dramatically accelerates the withdrawal process
徹底戒除毒癮
and kills the addiction.
副作用很厲害
The side effects are brutal,
所以在這里是非法的
which is why it's outlawed here.
惡心  嘔吐  產生幻覺
Nausea, vomiting, some hallucinations.
暴力的  讓人精神錯亂的幻覺
Violent, mind-bending hallucinations.
有用嗎
Does it work?
有用
It does.
相信我
Take my word.
從蒙特祖瑪的大廳
From the halls of Montezuma
到的黎波里的海岸
to the shores of Tripoli
在空中  在陸地  在海洋
We fight our country's battles
我們為祖國而戰
in air, on land and sea...
說話  你這混蛋
Say something, you motherfucker.
別光是站在那兒
Don't just stand there.
說話
Say something...
先是為了權利與自由而戰
First to fight for right and freedom
讓我們的榮譽干干凈凈
and to keep our honor clean
我們驕傲的宣稱
We are proud to claim the title
我們是美國海軍陸戰隊
of United States marine.
Of United States marine.
天吶
God...
滾開
Get out.
Get out!
你們他媽給我吃了什么
What the fuck did you give me?!
不
No...
給我
Give me that!
[阿語]
放開我
Get off me!
放開
Get off!
[阿語]
放開我  不
Get off me, no!
[阿語]
他現在會睡著
He'll sleep now.
一會兒
For a while.
也許我們應該用固話打給索爾
Maybe we should just call Saul's landline,
啟動語音激活
trigger the voice activation,
復查我們的跟蹤程序
double-check our tracking program.
是可以
We could.
但是
But...?
這棟房子租給了
This house is leased to
特拉維夫的一個航運集團
a shipping consortium out of Tel Aviv.
我覺得背后肯定有摩薩德的影子
It's got Mossad written all over it.
是  但如果就只是個監控臺
Yeah, but what if it's just a monitoring station,
或是情報傳送點呢
or a dead drop?
那我們就他媽是在浪費時間
Then we're wasting our fucking time.
你看到了嗎
Are you gettin' this?
你還活著
You're alive.
不是什么好事
That wasn't a given.
想喝水嗎
Want some water?
為什么不把我留在那里自生自滅呢
Why couldn't you have just left me there to die?
你知道我不能那么做
I think you know that wasn't really an option.
所以
So...
現在怎么辦
...What now?
那取決于你
That'll be up to you.
審訊嗎
A trial?
但不是我干的
'cause I didn't do it.
你是在說中情局的爆炸嗎
You talking about bombing the CIA?
我比較相信你的說法
I'm inclined to agree.
但你的罪行不是在那里開始或結束的
But your transgressions don't begin or end there.
我不打算糾結那件事
And I'm not about to engage in a back and forth
某種程度上你也是受害者
where you somehow end up the victim.
我們都知道你做了什么
We both know what you've done.
我們都知道你是什么人
We both know what you are.
一個給自己挖下無底深坑的人
A man who's dug himself into a hole so deep,
你知道自己無路可逃
common sense'd tell you there's no way out.
但我要告訴你  也許還有一線生機
I am telling you, though, that there might be.
怎么辦
How?
我給你提供一個機會
I'm offering you a chance
再次成為海軍陸戰隊員
to be a marine again.
成為那個
The man you were...
被他們毀掉之前的人
...before they broke you.
求求你
Please.
不要再來了
No more.
我已經完了
I'm done.
你沒有
You are not.
你會做這最后一件事
You will do this one last thing.
不
No.
殺了我吧
So kill me.
現在就殺了我
Kill me now.
你想死是吧
You want to die, huh?
我們等著瞧
We'll see about that.
把他扔下船
Put him overboard.
去他媽的  我要下去
Fuck this shit. I'm going in.
別去  他會上來的
Don't. He'll come up.
我不信
I don't believe this.
操  我們快下去
Fuck it. Let's go.
拉住他
Pull him...
他像塊石頭一樣沉下去了
He went down like a stone.
完全沒有求生的欲念
No attempt to save himself whatsoever.
現在他絕食了
Now he's refusing to eat.
喂他吃
Make him.
你打算讓我們怎么做
How do you expect us to do that?
強制喂食不會嗎
It's called force-feeding.
恕我直言  長官
All due respect, sir,
這家伙就是個廢人
the guy's a waste of space.
我建議你們  無論對他有什么想法
Now, I suggest whatever you've got in mind for him,
六個月后再說吧
just push it six months.
讓我們來好好處理
Let us do this thing right.
你那堆推心置腹的廢話說完了嗎
You done letting us in on your thought process?
是的  長官
Yes, sir.
喂他吃飯
Get him to eat.
他說得對
He's right, you know.
我們的時間不多了
Our window's closing fast.
勿失良機  索爾
It's now or never, Saul.
你感覺怎么樣
How you feeling?
好像你真的關心一樣
As if you actually cared.
我在這兒有時間思考
You know, I've had time to think here.
我不斷地回想事實
And I keep coming back to the fact
如果沒有你的許可
that this bullet in my shoulder
我肩膀里絕不會有這顆子彈
would never have happened without your okay.
你當時的舉動會連累整個任務
You were about to compromise the mission.
我是想證明布洛迪的清白
I was about to clear Brody.
你說過你會支持的
You said you were behind that.
證明布洛迪的清白
"Clear Brody."
那意味著什么
What does that even mean?
你騙了我
So you lied to me.
你真想談這個
I don't think you want to go there--
到底是誰騙誰
who lied to whom.
布洛迪偷偷溜出境
Brody slipping out of the country
與此同時  你不省人事長達14小時
while you were unconscious for 14 hours.
你覺得我會相信嗎
You think I believed that for a second?
你知道我當時在加拉加斯  你該給我留言的
You know I was in Caracas, you should left me a message.
你不想知道他的近況嗎
Don't you want to know how he is?
他怎么樣
How is he?
不怎么樣
He's not well.
你對他做了什么
What did you do to him?
這個問題背后的推測
You know, the assumptions behind that question
充滿偏見  嚇到我了
are so misguided, it frightens me.
我發現他時  情況已經很糟
I found him in a bad way.
相信我
Believe me.
那不是我想要的
It wasn't something I wanted.
他在哪兒
Where is he?
弗吉尼亞州
In Virginia.
奈克壩基地
At Dam Neck.
我找了一個特別行動小組幫助他康復
Got a special ops team trying to get him in shape.
康復之后呢
In shape for what?
我正想和你談這個
That's what I wanted to talk about.
我設了個局
I have a play.
牽涉到了布洛迪
It involves Brody.
我希望你能說服他
And I'm hoping you'll convince him.
這關乎到所有人的利益
It's in everyone's interest.
你告訴過我賈瓦迪是個局
You told me Javadi was the play.
他是
He is.
布洛迪是下一步
Brody's the next phase.
你為什么需要我
And you need me why?
我猜他已經拒絕你了
I'm assuming he already turned you down.
我們還沒到那一步
We didn't get that far.
正如我所說  他情況不好
Like I said, he's not well.
什么局  你有什么好主意
So, what is it? What's your big idea?
達尼什·阿克巴里
Darnish Akbari.
伊朗革命衛隊的首領
Head of Iran's Revolutionary Guard.
對
Right.
賈瓦迪的上司
Javadi's boss.
他還是和平的最大障礙
And the single greatest impediment to peace.
我想除掉他
I want him gone.
祝你好運
Well, good luck with that.
布洛迪能接觸到他
Brody can get to him.
怎么接觸
How?
作為中情局炸彈襲擊者
As the Langley bomber.
布洛迪去那里尋求政治庇護
Brody seeks political asylum there.
和阿克巴里會面  干掉他
Gets an audience with Akbari, takes him out.
賈瓦迪繼承他的衣缽
Javadi's the heir apparent.
他會掌權
He ascends the throne,
然后從伊朗最重要人物前二十
and he goes from being one of the 20 most important people
轉變為前三
in Iran to one of three.
不過他是我們的人
Only he's working for us.
布洛迪干掉他
Brody takes him out?
是的
Yes.
拜托  索爾  你胃口太大了
Come on, Saul, you're reaching.
阿克巴里的安保措施比阿亞圖拉還嚴密
Akbari's better protected than the Ayatollah.
布洛迪總能絕處逢生
Brody's got a knack for getting into tight places.
他之前就做到過
He's done it before.
那充其量就是個自殺性任務
At best it's a suicide mission.
不  他在外面有一個團隊
No, he'll have a team on the ground.
你想讓我說服他這么做
And you expect me to convince him of this?
我希望你能好好考慮
I expect you to consider deeply
讓美國線人打入伊朗權力金字塔的最頂端
the upside of placing a U.S. asset at the very top of
所帶來的益處
the Iranian food chain.
這是我希望的
That's what I expect.
賈瓦迪不僅會是情報來源
Javadi won't be just an intelligence source.
他會控制著
He'll be in control
整個伊朗安全機構
of the entire Iranian security apparatus.
那也不意味著他會洗心革面或是裝死
That doesn't mean he'll roll over and play dead.
我知道
I know.
但他可以做些什么
But he can do something.
從而打破僵局
Something to break the logjam.
且無需挑起另一場戰爭
Something besides another war.
并改變目前的現實
Something that'll change the facts on the ground.
這就足夠了
Just enough.
兩個國家已經有三十多年
So two countries that haven't been able to communicate
都沒能進行交流了
for over 30 years
只有通過恐怖主義行動和威懾行為
except through terrorist actions and threats...
才能讓彼此坐下來談談
...can sit down and talk.
計劃就是這樣  卡莉
That's the play, Carrie.
此舉難道不值得你付出嗎
Tell me it's not worth your time.
布洛迪  我想告訴你
Brody, I want you to know
我今天才知道你在這里
that I didn't know you were here until today.
我一聽到消息就馬上趕來了
I came as soon as I heard.
如果我有什么能幫到你  就跟我說
Tell me if there's anything I can do for you.
什么事都行
Anything.
他最遲何時需要準備好
When do you need him ready by?
本月二十七號
27th of this month.
怎么這么急
Why so soon?
那天是洛克哈特參議員
It's the day Senator Lockhart's
任職聽證開始的日子
confirmation hearings begin.
是啊
Right.
告訴我他在加拉加斯遇到了什么事
Tell me what happened to him in Caracas.
就我們了解  簡直一團糟
A world of shit as far as we know.
他在哥倫比亞邊境腹部中彈
He was gut-shot at the Columbian border.
差點送了命
Nearly died.
我猜還對止痛藥上了癮
Got hooked on the painkillers, I guess.
還在某個清真寺里出了事
There was also an incident at a mosque.
一位伊瑪目和他的妻子被殺
An imam and his wife were murdered.
都因為他嗎
Because of him?
就因為他
Because of him.
我需要一輛車
I need a vehicle.
你的胳膊怎么了
What happened to your arm?
玩懸掛滑翔摔的
Hang gliding accident.
真的假的
For real?
去他媽的中情局  巴拉茲
Fucking CIA, Baraz.
你有什么好問她的
What are you asking her questions for?
就隨便聊聊
Just making conversation.
下個路口左轉
It's the next left.
現在怎么辦
What now?
我們等著
Now we wait.
我們盯了這座房子二十四小時
We sat on the house for 24 hours.
出入過的只有這個人
And this is the only person who ever came in or out.
天吶
Oh, Christ.
你認識他嗎
You know him?
恐怕是的
Yeah, I'm afraid so.
他是什么人
Who is he?
我妻子的一個朋友
A friend of my wife's.
他叫阿倫·伯納德
His name is Alain Bernard.
他們在孟買認識的
She met him in Mumbai.
他們在那邊有過一段關系
They struck up a relationship there,
后來還有沒有繼續就不知道了
which may or may not be ongoing.
我也不想問這個  索爾
I hate to ask this, Saul,
不過  你覺得米拉知道嗎
but do you think Mira's aware?
他是以色列情報人員這事嗎
That he's an Israeli intelligence officer?
不知道
No.
迷戀上這家伙是她唯一的罪過
Falling for the guy is her only crime.
你想讓我做什么
What do you want me to do?
現在嗎
For the time being?
抓住他
Pick him up,
把他丟進地洞里關著去
put him in a dark fucking hole.
那洛克哈特呢
What about Lockhart?
他在其中扮演什么角色
How does he fit into the equation?
我大概漏了一條線索
I think I buried a lead.
什么意思
Meaning what?
這家伙離開安全屋以后
After our guy left the safe house,
我跟蹤他到了彼得餐廳
I followed him to Pete's Diner,
在國會山
Capitol Hill.
丹娜
Dana?
丹娜  丹...
Dana? Dan...
你們這群混蛋  讓我出去
Hey, assholes, let me out!
布洛迪
Brody...
放開我
Get off me!
天吶
Oh...God...
-放我出去  -放松
- Let me the hell out! - Relax!
布洛迪
Brody!
混賬東西
Motherfucker!
丹娜  是我
Dana, it's me!
丹娜
Dana!
-回去  -放開我
- Get back... - Get off of me!
丹娜
Dana!
媽的  丹娜
Fuck. Dana!
她聽不見的  布洛迪
She can't hear you, Brody.
你這個賤人
You...you bitch.
你這個臭婊子
You fucking bitch.
-他在嗎  -您有預約嗎
- Is he in? - Is he expecting you?
先生  您不能進去
Sir, you can't go in there.
反正那晚我還要招待一位籌款人
I'm hosting a fund-raiser that night anyway.
我得掛了
Listen, I got to go.
搞什么鬼  索爾
What the hell, Saul?
這是什么東西
What is this?
打開它
Open it.
你能解釋一下嗎
Care to explain?
阿倫·伯納德為《世界報》寫了一篇我的簡介
Alain Bernard is writing a profile on me for Le Monde.
二十分鐘之前
20 minutes ago,
阿倫·伯納德承認自己是以色列情報人員
Alain Bernard admitted to being an asset of Israeli intelligence.
這與我有何相干
And I should be concerned about this... Why?
他聲稱自己曾經將一系列從我家中
Because he claims he passed you information obtained
竊聽到的信息告知于你
from a listening device planted in my home.
扯淡
That's preposterous.
是嗎
Is it?
我一通電話打給貝納永大使
One call to ambassador Benayoun,
這馬上就會成為一次國際事件
it would be an international incident.
再一通電話打給《華盛頓郵報》
A second call to The Post,
你的照片馬上就能登上
and your picture'd be on the front page
全國報紙的頭版頭條
of every newspaper in the country.
你想怎樣
What do you want?
我想要時間
Time.
時間
Time?
只要你把就任局長一事
Postpone your confirmation
推遲到下月中旬
until the middle of next month,
我可以保證這些信息不曝光
and these'll never see the light of day.
我沒搞懂
I don't understand.
這只是個簡單的請求而已
It's a simple request.
再給我幾周時間
Give me a few more weeks.
我不是這個意思
That's not what I meant.
你可以借機一舉打垮我
You could destroy me with this.
繼續穩坐局長一職
You could guarantee your own tenure as director.
為什么要放我一馬
Why are you letting me off the hook?
因為我不想讓我的妻子蒙羞  參議員
Because it would humiliate my wife, senator.
況且這也會讓中情局的名聲掃地
And because it would damage the agency badly.
同意嗎
We have a deal?
成交
We do.
希望你已經可以平心靜氣地跟我談談了
I was hoping you've calmed down enough to talk.
丹娜怎么會在那么偏僻的地方
What's Dana doing cleaning motel rooms
-打掃汽車旅館  -怎么了
- in the middle of nowhere? - Why?
這有什么問題嗎
Is something wrong with that?
-做個鐘點工  -這他媽不是重點
- Being a maid? - There's nothing Wrong with that,
我就是想知道
goddamn it, I just want to know
我女兒到底怎么了
what's going on with my daughter!
先喝點水  然后我們再談丹娜的事
Drink it, and I'll tell you about Dana.
慢點喝  不然會惡心
Slowly, or you'll be sick.
好了
There.
到底怎么回事
Now, what's going on?
她這段日子過得不好  布洛迪
Well, she's had a rough time, Brody.
她輟學了
She dropped out of school.
搬到外面去住
She moved out of the house.
還改了自己的姓
She changed her last name.
帶我回那個汽車旅館
Take me back to the motel.
不可能
That's not gonna happen.
看在上帝的份上  卡莉
For Christ's sake, Carrie.
我告訴過你
I told you.
如果你想再見她一面
If you want to see her again...
別再耍我了  卡莉
Quit your fucking games, Carrie!
我要直視她的雙眼
I need to look her in the eye.
告訴她我是無辜的
I want her to know I'm innocent!
你要是一直吼的話  那我們就沒必要談了
If you keep yelling, this conversation is over.
我想讓這兩個人出去  你能乖乖的嗎
Now I would like to tell these two men to leave, can I do that?
你想怎樣
What do you want?
跟索爾·貝倫森的要求一樣對吧
The same thing as Saul Berenson, I'm guessing.
什么重歸海軍陸戰隊的鬼話
Some bullshit about me being a marine again?
那你想怎樣  布洛迪
What do you want, Brody?
你一直夢寐以求的是什么
What have you always wanted?
一個贖罪的機會
A chance at redemption.
我再說最后一遍  卡莉
For the last time, Carrie.
炸彈不是我放的
I didn't do the bombing.
就算別人不知道  你也該知道
You of all people should know that.
我說的不是炸彈襲擊案
I'm not talking about the bombing.
而是自殺式炸彈背心
I'm talking about the suicide vest.
我說的是伊麗莎白·蓋恩斯之死
I'm talking about the death of Elizabeth Gaines
還有國務院外的兩名特勤局特工
and those two secret service agents outside the State Department.
以及加拉加斯的伊瑪目和他妻子遇害
I'm talking about what happened to that imam and his wife in Caracas.
照索爾說的做
Do what Saul is asking.
-你希望我怎么做  -我希望你
- What you're asking? - All right, what I'm asking.
就算不為自己  也為丹娜考慮
If not for your sake, then for Dana's.
否則的話  即使告訴她你是無辜的
Otherwise, telling her you're innocent is just...
也不過是又一個謊言
...is just one more lie.
瞧我這副樣子  卡莉
Look at me, Carrie.
你現在讓我出去買包煙都成問題
You couldn't send me out for a pack of cigarettes right now.
我們會幫你做好準備
We'll get you ready.
但要你愿意配合才行
You just have to be willing.
瞧是誰跑出來玩了
Well, look who's come out to play.
也該出來了
About fucking time.
征得你媽同意了嗎
Did you get mommy's permission?
大伙都給我閉嘴
Hey, shut the fuck up, everybody.
沿著這邊跑
We're going this way.
準備好了嗎
You ready?
快點
Come on.
站起來
On your feet.
別動  他得靠自己
No. He needs to do it by himself.
什么時候能繼續跑
Tell me when you're good to go again.
就現在
Now.
跟上
Go.
十六天后
找到莫桑比克馬普托市
Find Maputo, Mozambique.
接收頻率是多少
What's the frequency?
3265千赫
Khz 3265.
當地人用什么語言交流
What language are they speaking?
葡萄牙語
Portuguese.
最后三張牌分別是什么
Bottom three cards?
梅花八
Eight of clubs.
紅桃十
Ten of hearts.
黑桃J
Jack of spades?
拼出她的姓
Spell her last name.
B-a-c-z-e-w-s-k-i  比謝夫斯基
Uh, B-a-c-z-e-w-s-k-i. Baczewski.
這上面說她比誰還火辣
It says here she's hotter than what?
-喬治婭·阿斯法特  -誰說的
- Georgia Asphalt? -And who said that?
電影《我心狂野》
尼古拉斯·凱奇和勞拉·鄧恩分別飾演賽勒和魯拉
《我心狂野》里的魯拉·撫琴
Lula Fortune to Sailor Ripley
對賽勒· 黎普列說的
in Wild at Heart.
全中
Fucking-a right.
你和她之間有什么故事
So, you guys got something going on?
沒有
No.
得了吧
Come on, man,
從她打量你的眼神就能看出端倪
I've seen the way she's checking you out
你當時沒在看她
when you're not looking.
真的沒什么
There's nothing.
真的
Seriously?
Seriously.
這么說你不介意
So, you don't mind if I...
我去泡她了
If I hit that shit then, right?
你看  還說沒什么
See? There is something.
我就知道
I knew it.
真的沒什么  你盡管去
No, go ahead. Really.
我只是和你開玩笑
Nah, man, I'm just fucking with you.
我結婚了
I'm married.
剛有了第一個孩子
And, uh, we just had our first kid.
是個男孩
It's a boy.
他叫德文
Name's Devon.
你怎么從來沒提過
How come I didn't know that?
因為我
Just...
不太愿意談及我的家庭
I don't like talking about my family.
迷信使然
Superstitious.
五分鐘后開會
Hey, we're on in five.
在簡報室
In the briefing room.
這一帶區域的伊朗巡邏隊并非全天候執勤
Iranian patrols in the area are intermittent.
但訓練有素  裝備精良
But they are well-trained and equipped.
此外  離這里七十英里處的畢扎爾
Also, there is also an IRIAF base
是伊朗的空軍基地
in Bijar, 70 miles away,
換句話說  隨時可以調配空中火力支持
which means they can call in air support.
他們都有什么飛機
What kind of planes are we talking?
有幾架是兩伊戰爭時期
Uh, some French-built F-1 Mirages impounded
從伊拉克收繳的法國F-1幻影戰斗機
from Iraq after the First Gulf War
還有六架中國制造的蘇24戰斗機
and six Chinese Su-24s.
不好意思  可以回到剛才的問題嗎
Excuse me, can we back up a minute?
可以
Sure.
他們押送我至邊境處
The guys gets me to the border...
然后我示意投降
where I surrender myself?
沒錯
Correct.
選擇馬里萬郡是因為很多基地組織指揮官
We chose Marivan because several Al-Qaeda commanders
同樣在那里尋求政治庇護
also asked for political asylum there.
之后呢  等人空載我去德黑蘭
What happens then? I get flown to Tehran?
經過一段時間審查之后  我們的預期是那樣的
After a period of vetting, yeah, that's our expectation.
好的  你憑什么認為我能夠接近
Okay, but what makes you think I'll ever get close enough
阿克巴里將軍并完成刺殺
to General Akbari to take him out?
你將受到革命英雄的待遇
You'll be treated as a hero of the revolution.
很多高級官員  比如將軍
The senior members of the regime, like the general,
會迫不及待想利用你的宣傳價值
want to take advantage of your propaganda value.
而且賈瓦迪將作為引薦人
Plus Javadi's on the ground
安排你和將軍的會面
to facilitate a meeting between the two of you.
但如果不知道暗殺行動結束的時間地點的話
But if we don't know where or when the assassination goes down...?
你是在擔心撤離計劃
You're concerned about our extraction plan.
任務完成之后  該如何全身而退
How we're gonna get you out of there once it's done?
是的
Yeah.
我正準備說
I was just getting to that.
你一進入邊境
Once you're inserted at the border,
隨行隊伍里的四名人員
four members of your team
會沿路南上儂得衫
will continue south to Nodesheh,
之后翻山越嶺  穿過平原
where they cross the mountains and make their way overland
行軍至拉溫莎
to Lavasan,
德黑蘭外圍的一個小城市
a small city just outside Tehran.
那里有當地的反叛組織
Opposition groups there have provided us
提供的安全屋
with a safe house.
我們領先一步
We've already gone ahead
安全衛星通信設備已安裝完畢
and put in secure satcom.
碰頭暗號是
Our code there is...
[波斯語]
你從什么時候開始抽煙的
Since when do you smoke?
我不抽
I don't.
我沒在抽
I'm not.
只是裝個樣子
It just looks like I'm smoking.
瞧  就當沒發生過
There. It never happened.
你什么也沒看見
You saw nothing.
什么也沒有
Nothing.
話說...
Look...
我照你說的做了
I did what you asked.
按你的意愿行事
I'm doing what you want.
現在該帶我去見丹娜了
Now you told me you'd take me to see Dana again.
我是說等你回來以后
I meant after you get back.
算了吧  卡莉
Come on, Carrie.
你我都知道此行兇多吉少
We both know that's a long shot.
這么多風雨都熬過來了
We made it this far.
這倒是
That's true.
我承認  我有過懷疑
I admit, I had my doubts.
所以你才刻意保持距離吧
Is that why you've kept your distance?
沒關系的
Hey, it's fine.
這是你的權利
You're entitled.
六小時后你就要出發了
You're loading out in six hours.
我不知道能否及時把你送回基地
I'm not sure I can get you off the base and back in time.
不見到丹娜  我是不會走的
Well, I'm not leaving until I see Dana again.
在119號房間
It's there. 119.
布洛迪  有些事我得告訴你
Brody, there's something you need to know.
在丹娜更改姓氏
Before she changed her name,
離家出走之前
before she left home...
她在醫院待過一陣
Dana was hospitalized.
在爆炸案發生后兩周后
About two weeks after the bombing...
她曾企圖自殺
she tried to kill herself.
誰啊
Who is it?
丹娜  是我
Dana, it's me.
是爸爸
It's your dad.
你是怎么找到我的
How did you find me?
有卡莉幫忙
Carrie.
我能進去嗎
Can I come in?
拜托了  丹娜
Dana, please?
謝謝
Thank you.
我一定得見你
I had to see you.
好吧
Okay.
你見到了
You have.
親愛的  我真的很抱歉
Oh, my baby, I'm so sorry.
沒這個必要
Don't be.
你現在過得還好嗎
How are you now?
你到底來干什么
Why are you here?
我只是想告訴你
I just wanted to tell you that
那些人指責我干的那些事情  我是被冤枉的
all those things those people said I did, I didn't do.
好的
Fine.
好的  很好
Fine, good.
那些人不是我殺的
I didn't kill all those people.
不是我
It wasn't me.
不是我干的
I didn't do it.
我馬上要走了
And I have to leave soon.
幾小時后就走
In a few hours.
我只是想在臨走前見見你
But I just wanted to see you before I go.
你見到了
You did.
你就從來沒想過
Did you ever, for one second,
我是不是想見到你呢
think about if I wanted to see you?
你想聽我說什么
What do you want to hear?
說你是好爸爸嗎
That you were a good dad?
無論發生什么事  都沒關系嗎
That despite everything, it's all okay?
你想讓我說什么
What do you want me to say?
這樣吧
Look...
拿去
Look, here...
拿張紙寫下來
Here, just write it down.
你寫什么我就說什么
Really, just write it down and I will say it to you...
只要你答應
as long as you promise
再也別讓我見到你了
I will never have to see you again.
你們倆都是
Either of you.
我會從德黑蘭回來的
I will come back from Tehran.
我知道
I know you will.
不只是為了她
And not just for her.
你們他媽的去哪了
Where the fuck were you?
他想找人談心
He wanted to talk.
還有四十五分鐘他就要出發了
He's got 45 minutes to load out.
他準備就緒了
He's all set.
你把他帶出基地了
You took him off base.
他威脅說不干了  索爾
He threatened to pull out, Saul.
出去可能會發生各種意外
Anything could've happened out there.
可是沒發生
But it didn't.
我真他媽對你無語了
I am truly at a fuckin' loss with you.
能有點信心嗎  索爾
Have a little faith, Saul.
兩周前  你根本沒法實施行動
Two weeks ago, there was no operation.
因為我  現在才得以行動
Now there is, because of me.
我真心希望你能明白這點
I really need you to get that.
為了讓本次行動成功
Because in order for us to pull this thing off,
我們必須得想個辦法
we're gonna have to find a way
重新建立彼此間的信任
to trust each other again.
或者想個好辦法假裝互相信任
Or at least come up with a really great plan for faking it.
布洛迪
Brody...
到那邊再見
See you on the other side.